<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Nikolai Köhler</title><link>https://nklkhlr.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in News on Nikolai Köhler</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nklkhlr.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog</title><link>https://nklkhlr.github.io/blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nklkhlr.github.io/blog/</guid><description>In Progress&amp;hellip;
I&amp;rsquo;m planning to write (somewhat regularly) about
machine learning and topological data analysis applications in computational biology introductions to metabolomics data-analysis for experimentalists occassionally off-topic stuff like communication, experiences as a PhD student etc.</description></item><item><title>Talks</title><link>https://nklkhlr.github.io/talks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nklkhlr.github.io/talks/</guid><description>Talks Reaction-Centered Metabolic Network Analysis
13/10/2022, Munich Metabolomics Meeting 2022
Slides
Lipid network and moiety analysis for revealing enzymatic dysregulation and mechanistic alterations from lipidomics data
10/10/2022, ICSB 2022
Slides
Lipid metabolic network analysis for inferring mechanistic changes in enzyme activity
21/03/2022, 10\(^{th}\) Workshop in Lipidomics
Slides
Network-based Lipidomics Analysis using the Lipid Network Explorer (best presentation award)
01/12/2021, Virtual Podium Asia Pacific
Slides
Investigation Global Lipidome Alterations with the Lipid Newtork Explorer</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://nklkhlr.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 09:56:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nklkhlr.github.io/publications/</guid><description>2023 Journal Articles Lipid network and moiety analysis for revealing enzymatic dysregulation and mechanistic alterations from lipidomics data
Tim Daniel Rose\(^{\dagger}\) , Nikolai Köhler\(^{\dagger}\) , Lisa Falk, Lucie Klischat, Olga Lazareva and Josch Konstantin Pauling
Briefings in Bioinformatics, 2023
Citation
Software and Computational Tools for LC-MS-Based Epilipidomics: Challenges and Solutions
Tito Damiani, Stefano Bonciarelli, Gerhard G Thallinger, Nikolai Köhler, Christoph A Krettler, Arif K Salihoğlu, Ansgar Korf, Josch K Pauling, Tomáš Pluskal, Zhixu Ni, Laura Goracci</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://nklkhlr.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nklkhlr.github.io/about/</guid><description>I am a PhD Student in Bioinformatics in the LipiTUM group at the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics at the Technical University of Munich. The main focus of my research currently lies on computational methods for the interpretation and (multi-omics) integration of metabolomics data in a systems biology context. For developing these algorithms I am utilising methods from (classical) graph-theory, machine learning and deep-learning. I am also interested in applying computational models to real-world data.</description></item><item><title>Teaching</title><link>https://nklkhlr.github.io/teaching/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nklkhlr.github.io/teaching/</guid><description> Thesis Supervision Bioinformatics &amp;ldquo;Development of a Deep Learning Model for the Detection and Prediction of Characteristic Fragmentation Patterns in Lipid Mass Spectra&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Network Integration of Metabolome and Microbiome Data using Local Search Optimisation&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Imputing Common Lipids to Improve Network Connectivity of Lipid Metabolic Networks&amp;rdquo; Molecular Biotechnology &amp;ldquo;A Network-based Meta-Analysis to Link Nutritional Metabolites to Lipid Metabolism and Related Diseases&amp;rdquo; Lectures and Seminars Computational Biochemistry (Winter 20/21, Winter 21/22, Winter 22/23) Systems BioMedicine Course Project Supervision (Winter 20/21, Winter 21/22, Winter 22/23) Problem Based Learning (Winter 21/22)</description></item></channel></rss>