<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Nikolai Köhler</title><link>https://nklkhlr.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in News on Nikolai Köhler</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nklkhlr.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog</title><link>https://nklkhlr.github.io/blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 10:09:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nklkhlr.github.io/blog/</guid><description>Following&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Talks</title><link>https://nklkhlr.github.io/talks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 10:09:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nklkhlr.github.io/talks/</guid><description>Following&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://nklkhlr.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 09:57:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nklkhlr.github.io/about/</guid><description>I am a PhD Student in Bioinformatics in the LipiTUM group at the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics at the Technical University of Munich. The main focus of my research currently lies on computational methods for the interpretation and (multi-omics) integration of metabolomics data in a systems biology context. For developing these algorithms I am utilising methods from (classical) graph-theory, machine learning and deep-learning. I am also interested in applying computational models to real-world data.</description></item><item><title>Teaching</title><link>https://nklkhlr.github.io/teaching/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 09:57:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nklkhlr.github.io/teaching/</guid><description>Thesis Supervision Bioinformatics &amp;ldquo;Development of a Deep Learning Model for the Detection and Prediction of Characteristic Fragmentation Patterns in Lipid Mass Spectra&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Network Integration of Metabolome and Microbiome Data using Local Search Optimisation&amp;rdquo; Molecular Biotechnology &amp;ldquo;A Network-based Meta-Analysis to Link Nutritional Metabolites to Lipid Metabolism and Related Diseases&amp;rdquo; Lectures and Seminars Computational Biochemistry (Winter 20/21)</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://nklkhlr.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 09:56:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nklkhlr.github.io/publications/</guid><description>Journal Articles 2021 Investigating Global Lipidome Alterations with the Lipid Network Explorer.
Nikolai Köhler\(^{\dagger}\) , Tim Daniel Rose\(^{\dagger}\) , Lisa Falk and Josch Konstantin Pauling
Metabolites, 2021
Citation
Liver Lipids of Patients with Hepatitis B and C and Associated Hepatocellular Carcinoma.
Haberl EM, Weiss TS, Peschel G, Weigand K, Köhler N, Pauling JK, Wenzel JJ, Höring M, Krautbauer S, Liebisch G, Buechler C
International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 2021</description></item></channel></rss>